<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Addy</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Addy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Andrew Tate</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/andrew-tate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/andrew-tate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These are some things that I have learned from watching Andrew Tate&amp;rsquo;s videos:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;politicians&#34;&gt;Politicians&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Politicians are not stupid&lt;/strong&gt;: Do not think that politicians are stupid; that is a very optimistic view. They are not stupid; they know what they are doing. It is you who is confused because you think they work for you. You believe the politicians are your representatives, and when they don&amp;rsquo;t represent your interests, you think they are dumb. No! They work for someone else. They use this democracy thing to only allow you to accept it. They are doing exactly what the people who pay them want them to do; in fact, they are doing it fantastically. Your confusion stems from thinking that they care about you. They never have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;freedom&#34;&gt;Freedom&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to maintain illusion of freedom&lt;/strong&gt;: By putting freaks to the front. This person chopped his dick off, see we are free!(You are free to hurt yourself). But do not be fooled you are not free to say anything against the power, anything important.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;anxiety&#34;&gt;Anxiety&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have anxiety because you should be anxious, Why is a mouse anxious ? Same for you! The large bear does not get anxious. A mouse think a noise (anxious) it might kill me! Bear thinks I might want to kill it! Its a different vibe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anxiety is not a disorder - it is a natural conclusion of your ineptitude, its your soul giving you feedback. Anxiety is cured by strength.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dying ain&amp;rsquo;t so bad untill unless you die for a good reason. Dying is not the worst thing that can heppen, living without a purpose is the worst thing that can happen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CV</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My name is Aaditya Barak. I am a student of Electrical and Electronics Engineering at University Institute of Engineering and Technology, Chandigarh. I am a machine learning enthusiast and currently in third year of my undergraduate studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phone: +91-9896127290&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email: &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:aadityabarak472@gmail.com&#34;&gt;aadityabarak472@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GitHub: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AddyB0t&#34;&gt;https://github.com/AddyB0t&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;X: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/aadi29494&#34;&gt;https://x.com/aadi29494&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;technical-skills&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technical Skills&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Programming Languages&lt;/strong&gt;: Python, C, C++, MATLAB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Machine Learning &amp;amp; AI&lt;/strong&gt;: PyTorch, TensorFlow, Langchain, NumPy, Pandas, Hugging Face, Streamlit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internet of Things&lt;/strong&gt;: Arduino, Raspberry Pi, ESP32, 8085 Microprocessor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools &amp;amp; Technologies&lt;/strong&gt;: CX Programmer, NB Designer, P-Spice, Simulink, Jupyter Notebook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Courses&lt;/strong&gt;: Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Computer Vision, Natural Language Processing, Computer Networks, Operating Systems, Database Management Systems, Object Oriented Programming, Data Structures and Algorithms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;projects&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Projects&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;machine-learning-projects&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Machine Learning Projects&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;deepfake-detection-system&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deepfake Detection System&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developed a CNN-based deepfake detection model achieving 93% accuracy on unseen test data using TensorFlow and transfer learning from VGG16&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented face extraction preprocessing with OpenCV and evaluated performance using ROC curves, confusion matrices, and precision-recall metrics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;research-paper-summarization-tool&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Research Paper Summarization Tool&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developed an interactive Streamlit web application that uses OpenAI&amp;rsquo;s language models through LangChain to summarize complex research papers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created a user-friendly interface with customizable explanation styles, adjustable output lengths, and robust error handling for API interactions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;e-commerce-website-for-dropshipping&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;E-commerce Website for Dropshipping&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed and developed a responsive e-commerce website using Shopify for dropshipping business&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented product catalog, shopping cart functionality, and integrated payment gateway for seamless customer experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimized site performance with responsive design principles ensuring compatibility across desktop and mobile devices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;iot-projects&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IOT Projects&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;weather-station&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weather Station&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed a weather station using Arduino UNO, DHT11 sensor, and LCD display to measure temperature and humidity with 95% accuracy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented I2C communication protocol for efficient data transfer between components with real-time display capabilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;alcohol-detection-system&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alcohol Detection System&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed an alcohol detection device using Arduino UNO and MQ-3 sensor that triggers a buzzer alert when levels exceed a calibrated threshold&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented serial monitoring for real-time tracking with 95% detection accuracy and appropriate sensitivity adjustments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;smoke-detection-system&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smoke Detection System&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed a smoke detection device using Arduino UNO and MQ-3 sensor with 95% detection accuracy through proper calibration and testing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented real-time monitoring with buzzer alerts when smoke levels exceed predetermined safety thresholds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;smart-dustbin&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smart Dustbin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed an automated waste container that opens when a person approaches using ultrasonic sensor for proximity detection up to 20cm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Programmed Arduino to control servo motor with 2-second delay timing mechanism for proper lid operation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;blind-assistance-system&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blind Assistance System&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed a navigation aid for visually impaired individuals using Arduino UNO and HC-SR04 ultrasonic sensor to detect obstacles within 100cm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented variable feedback where buzzer beeps faster as obstacles get closer, with response time under 100ms for immediate feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;distance-measurement-system&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Distance Measurement System&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed a precise distance measurement system using Arduino UNO and HC-SR04 ultrasonic sensor with I2C LCD display for real-time readings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Achieved consistent performance with measurement range of 2-400cm, accuracy within ±1cm, and refresh rate of 2Hz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;password-based-door-lock-system&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Password-Based Door Lock System&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed a secure door locking system using Arduino UNO, 4x4 matrix keypad, and servo motor with LED indicators for lock status&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented error handling for incorrect attempts with 99% reliability and response time under 100ms for real-time security application&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;certifications&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Certifications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LangChain - Udemy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SQL(intermediate) - Sololearn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;achievements&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achievements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Qualified for Smart India Hackathon 2024 in the college-level selection round&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;positions-of-responsibility&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Positions of Responsibility&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Community Manager for an international Discord server of Machine Learning enthusiasts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lead Administrator for University&amp;rsquo;s E-Sports Discord community&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;education&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Education&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Degree&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Year&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Institution&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Bachelor of Engineering in Electrical and Electronics Engineering&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;2022-2026&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;University Institute of Engineering and Technology, Chandigarh&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;XII (CBSE)&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;2022&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Hansraj Public School, Panchkula&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;X (CBSE)&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;2020&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Hansraj Public School, Panchkula&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
